<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>risk on Tony On Risk</title>
    <link>/tags/risk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in risk on Tony On Risk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/risk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for Combining Expert Opinions</title>
      <link>/2019/08/18/resources-for-expert-opinion-pooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/18/resources-for-expert-opinion-pooling/</guid>
      <description>Methods for combining expert opinions for use in the creation of probability distributions in risk analysis is a hot topic right now. At least as hot as any quantitative information risk topic can get. I thought it might be helpful to bang out a quick post with some links and notes on the topic.
Here are a few resources where one might find answers or a starting point.
Some are inclined to simply average the results of expert parameter elicitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About Extreme Value Theory</title>
      <link>/2019/06/02/extreme-value-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/02/extreme-value-theory/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk about Extreme value theory - Wikipedia and information risk. I won’t throw down a bunch of R, because it’d basically just be a re-hash of the first reference listed below.
Instead, I’ll share my current thinking on where EVT might fit.
It fits when you&amp;rsquo;re interested in examining the end of the tail. When you might have a handful of extreme, low probability observations and you want to fit a distribution to those observations to help estimate a true maximum or for some reason think about just how extreme something might get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Zero-Sum Thinking Affecting Your Risk Decision?</title>
      <link>/2017/06/27/zero-sum-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/27/zero-sum-bias/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges we embrace in my line of work is the attempt to identify risk convergence and opportunities for risk reduction across multiple scenarios. It’s not uncommon for these opportunities to cut across business functions or risk assets. When I find these points of convergence I start looking for adjustments that reduce risk exposure and simultaneously improve the customer experience. If you can squeeze some cost savings out while you’re at it, that’s a banner day!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>