<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Scenario 1</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Scenario 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>This Year In Books</title>
      <link>/2019/12/19/2019-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/19/2019-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>This year I read .83 books per month, which is several more books than I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be allowed to read given I have two small children.
Fiction  House Made of Dawn by N. Scott Momaday - This is a wonderful book and opens with writing reminiscent of East of Eden. Brighton Rock by Graham Greene Under the Volcano by Malcolm Lowry  Stats, Risk, Etc.  Trading Bases by Joe Peta The Flaw of Averages by Sam Savage The Tyranny of Metrics by Jerry Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Development</title>
      <link>/2019/10/11/professional-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/11/professional-development/</guid>
      <description>As I was listening to Go Time podcast ep. 99 - Hiring and nurturing junior developers on the way into the office and noting the parallels to the &amp;ldquo;cyber-security talent shortage&amp;rdquo;, I kept thinking about the inconvenient truth of how and why hiring junior talent isn&amp;rsquo;t generally incentivized.
I think what we&amp;rsquo;re really missing here is a focus on transaction cost (economics), time horizon (economics), and ability to architect expectations for career progression holistically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Buffalo - Part 0.3</title>
      <link>/2019/08/23/buffalo-notes-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/23/buffalo-notes-pt2/</guid>
      <description>All notes are referencing buffalo 0.14.8 on Ubuntu.
Using buffalo generate resource myresourcename generated an actions file with an undefined: T i18n.Translator in the flash message template. No big deal and the generators are still pretty delightful.
No Templates Box Defined So, out of the gate I was receiving an error that no TemplatesBox was defined when making a request to /. At first I thought I needed to read up on templating and maybe I had screwed up the default index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for Combining Expert Opinions</title>
      <link>/2019/08/18/resources-for-expert-opinion-pooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/18/resources-for-expert-opinion-pooling/</guid>
      <description>Methods for combining expert opinions for use in the creation of probability distributions in risk analysis is a hot topic right now. At least as hot as any quantitative information risk topic can get. I thought it might be helpful to bang out a quick post with some links and notes on the topic.
Here are a few resources where one might find answers or a starting point.
Some are inclined to simply average the results of expert parameter elicitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Buffalo - Part 0.2</title>
      <link>/2019/08/10/buffalo-notes-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/10/buffalo-notes-pt1/</guid>
      <description>All notes are referencing buffalo 0.14.8 on Ubuntu.
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed is that the plugin framework may not be playing as described in the documentation. For example, installing the auth plugin.
buffalo plugins install github.com/gobuffalo/buffalo-auth
is supposed to, by my understanding, update the buffalo-plugins.toml file and go get the plugin for install. My experience however was that the command updated buffalo-plugins.toml, but did not install. Following tutorials and trying the g (generator) will result in an error: ERRO[0004] [PLUGIN] error loading plugin /home/username/go/bin/buffalo-auth: signal: killed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About Extreme Value Theory</title>
      <link>/2019/06/02/extreme-value-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/02/extreme-value-theory/</guid>
      <description>Let’s talk about Extreme value theory - Wikipedia and information risk. I won’t throw down a bunch of R, because it’d basically just be a re-hash of the first reference listed below.
Instead, I’ll share my current thinking on where EVT might fit.
It fits when you&amp;rsquo;re interested in examining the end of the tail. When you might have a handful of extreme, low probability observations and you want to fit a distribution to those observations to help estimate a true maximum or for some reason think about just how extreme something might get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel Slightly Better About Your Capability Maturity Model Work</title>
      <link>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</guid>
      <description>During the course of your information security management and reporting you may find yourself in need of a tool for soliciting feedback to assess program operational capabilities. It may be useful to employ a Capability Maturity Model to gauge the emotional current state of a given practice.
Once you’ve gathered responses, you have to decide what to do with them. It’s not uncommon to average out the responses and use that as an indication of level state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Apply Google&#39;s CausalImpact Package to Analyze Infosec Intervention</title>
      <link>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</guid>
      <description>Google released their CausalImpact package a few years ago and when they did my mind started racing with ideas for information security and information risk applications.
Imagine if you could propose a control, policy change or process improvement with an expected effect on a response variable, which would lead you to purposefully defining a way to measure intervention outcomes. Not bad. You go on to determine a number of covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dorking Around with CORS</title>
      <link>/2018/04/28/dorking-around-with-cors-and-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/28/dorking-around-with-cors-and-golang/</guid>
      <description>After tuning in to Absolute Appsec ep 2 the other day I got pretty interested in CORS security issues related to misconfiguration and dynamic origin handling. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but every once in a while I hear about a bug class, or maybe just a set of unintended consequences that I find particularly amusing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found that building a tool (no matter how poor), goes a long way toward a deeper understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Proxy Go net/http</title>
      <link>/2018/04/11/how-to-proxy-go-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/11/how-to-proxy-go-http/</guid>
      <description>I started playing around a bit (again) in Go recently and had a need to take a look at some requests I was generating. I wanted to take a look in ZAP to see how things were working and use that to make adjustments, etc.
Post is no big deal, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to forget how to do this. Also, there are several posts that don&amp;rsquo;t seem to actually work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Steak Eating and Gender</title>
      <link>/2018/02/20/gender-package-and-the-big-texan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/20/gender-package-and-the-big-texan/</guid>
      <description>Before we get too far down the trail on this, I’ll warn readers that this is a pink and blue post. It’s simple prediction using an interesting R package.
It’s important to consider the stakes (pun intended), when “enriching” a dataset with information that might introduce bias. Here, inaccuracies can occur by simple misspelling or just a slightly higher probability for the years selected…or other things.
That said, I wanted to get an idea of gender diversity in competitive steak eating competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Learn Apache Drill Together</title>
      <link>/2018/01/03/lets-learn-apache-drill-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/03/lets-learn-apache-drill-together/</guid>
      <description>Lets Learn Apache Drill Together! Querying cvs Files with Headers Default behavior is to ignore the first line and not use headers. You can change this by going to the storage tab in the web interface
Text Files: CSV, TSV, PSV - Apache Drill
Using COLUMNS[x] instead of columns[x] Query Failed: An Error Occurred org.apache.drill.common.exceptions.UserRemoteException: DATA_READ ERROR: Selected column &amp;lsquo;COLUMNS&amp;rsquo; must have name &amp;lsquo;columns&amp;rsquo; or must be plain &amp;lsquo;*&amp;rsquo; File Path file:_sample-data_some.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a iPod Classic Man</title>
      <link>/2017/12/31/speed-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/31/speed-it-up/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some learning on PluralSight thanks to a subscription through my employer. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed it, but one of the features I use all the time is 1.5X playback speed. I find that I can still get the content and it cuts down on the dead air and slow typing.
Now, I look for faster playback on everything and am kind of suprised when I can&amp;rsquo;t find it. However, I use one of these for my music and podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning Practice Pt1 - Steak Stats</title>
      <link>/2017/11/17/data-cleaning-practice-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/17/data-cleaning-practice-pt1/</guid>
      <description>Our family is in the habit of heading west. As such, we&amp;rsquo;ve passed through Amarillo, TX a time or two. I&amp;rsquo;ve even stopped into the Big Texan once for breakfast.
For miles down I-40 you&amp;rsquo;ll see billboards for this restaurant and brewery advertising a free 72oz steak, if you can eat it.
An office debate erupted amongst two of my colleagues over just what types of people end up beating the beast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Keys for Successful Products and Programs Before You Even Start</title>
      <link>/2017/11/15/product-and-program-success-before-you-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/15/product-and-program-success-before-you-start/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been an information security practitioner for more than a few years, you’ve likely witnessed your share of disappointing purchases, implementations and initiatives.
If you’ve been charged with managing multiple information security projects, you might have experienced a torrent of failure.
So, why are some initiatives destined for glory while others board the bullet train to the Abyss of Embarrassment? Don’t like that one? The budget incinerator?
Let’s take a look at applying value chain concepts while examining some of the external pressures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarting Conversation With Sarcastic Programming</title>
      <link>/2017/08/27/sarcastic-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/27/sarcastic-programming/</guid>
      <description>While killing time on Twitter the other day a Techlahoma tweet featuring WebVR and A-Frame grabbed my attention. If you know me, I’ve been excited about VR and AR for sometime (despite not having any VR or AR capable equipment). So, a color changing sphere that bounces is still fairly fun for me.
A-Frame makes creating WebVR experiences extremely accessible. This could be great for artists and those who might otherwise miss out on the medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You’re Going to Fail To Scale, Don’t - Part II</title>
      <link>/2017/07/15/fail-to-scale-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/15/fail-to-scale-part2/</guid>
      <description>First, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read Part I here&amp;rsquo;s the link. Now, on to Part II. If You’re Going to Fail To Scale, Don’t - Part II People hate to wait.
In Kaiser Fung’s book Numbers Rule Your World he discusses two congestion problem case studies. One relates to the grueling wait times at Disney attractions. The other is a study on ramp metering in Minneapolis.
Now, if you’re not familiar with ramp metering here’s the gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Zero-Sum Thinking Affecting Your Risk Decision?</title>
      <link>/2017/06/27/zero-sum-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/27/zero-sum-bias/</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges we embrace in my line of work is the attempt to identify risk convergence and opportunities for risk reduction across multiple scenarios. It’s not uncommon for these opportunities to cut across business functions or risk assets. When I find these points of convergence I start looking for adjustments that reduce risk exposure and simultaneously improve the customer experience. If you can squeeze some cost savings out while you’re at it, that’s a banner day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tony&#39;s Coffee Guide</title>
      <link>/2017/06/25/coffee-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/25/coffee-guide/</guid>
      <description>I drink quite a bit of coffee. It&amp;rsquo;s true.
Occasionally it comes up in conversation. It occurs that someone is bored with their beans and wants to class up their caffeine delivery. Maybe this is you.
Well, here are some of my favorites as of late. Check them out.
Top Picks  The best espresso that may ever enter your face comes out of San Jose, CA. Gamut from Chromatic won&amp;rsquo;t let you down with this consistently delicious espresso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You’re Going to Fail To Scale, Don’t - Part I</title>
      <link>/2017/05/30/fail-to-scale-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/30/fail-to-scale-part1/</guid>
      <description>Businesses that don’t deliver, don’t survive. Why should your information security program?
The organization has decided to spin up an information security program and you’re in charge.
You’ve heard of $framework and you declare adoption with less thought or ceremony than adopting a puppy. You decide that to support $framework you can write almost any nonsense and establish policy and process. You’ve got a champion with a corner office and things are going swell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Sankey!
Sankey diagrams for infosec</title>
      <link>/2017/05/19/sankey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/19/sankey/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, a tweet caught my eye.
It was something that I know I’d seen before, but it somehow had escaped my memory as to what it was called or how it was constructed. Well, it bugged me enough that I had to track it down.
It was the Sankey Chart.
tweet from @wendynather
 You can view the original tweet here.
As I am currently neck deep in writing an annual risk report it’d be easy for me to agree with the thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just a Test Post From Blogdown</title>
      <link>/2017/05/15/just-a-test-post-from-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/15/just-a-test-post-from-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>So, Yihui Xie gifted the RStats world with another presentation surface. Now you can easily produce Hugo generated blogs right from RStudio! Oh, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty great.
There are a few bloggers blogging on blogs about this blog generator, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve got the basics of github down you might just go to https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>