<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on One Scenario</title>
    <link>/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on One Scenario</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tony&#39;s Coffee Guide</title>
      <link>/blog/coffee%20guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/coffee%20guide/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I drink quite a bit of coffee.  It&amp;rsquo;s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally it comes up in conversation.  It occurs that someone is bored with their beans and wants to class up their caffeine delivery.  Maybe this is you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here are some of my favorites as of late.  Check them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-picks&#34;&gt;Top Picks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best espresso that may ever enter your face comes out of San Jose, CA.  Gamut from Chromatic won&amp;rsquo;t let you down with this consistently delicious espresso.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chromaticcoffee.com/gamut-espresso/&#34;&gt;http://www.chromaticcoffee.com/gamut-espresso/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Novel is doing wonderful things.  They keep a tight rotation, so there&amp;rsquo;s always something new and nothing specific to name, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been let down.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.novelcoffeeroasters.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.novelcoffeeroasters.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onyx Coffee Lab out of Bentonville, AR is absolutely killing it.  They&amp;rsquo;ve got an amazing space and do pretty much everything really well.  Worth a stop if you&amp;rsquo;re in the area.  Worth a try if you just want to order online.  Plus, they offer a new level of transparency in  &lt;a href=&#34;purchasing&#34;&gt;http://sprudge.com/point-sale-tranparency-reporting-onyx-coffees-new-website-118712.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://onyxcoffeelab.com/&#34;&gt;https://onyxcoffeelab.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1000 Faces is a little hit and miss.  They&amp;rsquo;ve brought forth a formidable Guji and if you can catch them when they&amp;rsquo;re running Suke Quto it&amp;rsquo;s worth an order.  The espressos, William &amp;amp; Maria, and Misty Valley I think of as an unremarkable, ok. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.1000facescoffee.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.1000facescoffee.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Populace puts out some really nice Ethiopians.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had their Guji and a Peruvian, I may end up checking out their cold brew blend at some point.  They&amp;rsquo;re reasonably priced and don&amp;rsquo;t have much to worry about on the shipping end.   &lt;a href=&#34;https://populace.coffee/&#34;&gt;https://populace.coffee/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to keep my notes here, but I don&amp;rsquo;t plan on spamming the RSS with updates.  Check back as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You’re Going to Fail To Scale, Don’t - Part I</title>
      <link>/blog/Fail-to-scale-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/Fail-to-scale-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses that don’t deliver, don’t survive.  Why should your information security program?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization has decided to spin up an information security program and you’re in charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard of &lt;em&gt;$framework&lt;/em&gt; and you declare adoption with less thought or ceremony than adopting a puppy.  You decide that to support &lt;em&gt;$framework&lt;/em&gt; you can write almost any nonsense and establish policy and process.  You’ve got a champion with a corner office and things are going swell.  You’re about to pull the big lever and let slip the dogs of war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How sure are you that you can handle what you’ve built?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your customers are placing orders and you don’t have inventory you’ve got two options.  Put them on a wait list or reject the order.   Neither instills great confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, imagine that the customer was forced at gunpoint to place the first order and in a week they’ll be forced to place another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now think for a minute about any process control gate that you’ve put in place by policy or governance.  What is the velocity and volume of items that need to come through that gate and what is the program’s capacity to handle them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many items can you handle per week?  You’ve got 52 weeks a year minus paid time off and sick days per FTE.  Now how many items do you have queuing?  What does that come to?  What degradation plan is in place for the loss of an FTE?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are clear problems with running your service offering at 100% when replacement can take months and some organizations are sponging up multiples of that.  Most often this is the result of seeking coverage without considering cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overused Euler diagram applies if you picked “fast and cheap” it’s probably not going to be very good.  If it&amp;rsquo;s a gate that everything has to pass through, it needs to be at least nearly-automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For time intensive, high quality efforts think boutique not big box.  You may have a valuable service offering, but its a tool to improve only those assets that are mission critical.  When you invest the time of these scarce resources you want to be sure that you’re gaining a net positive and the asset targeted is significantly more expensive than the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats all for now.  We’ll dig into congestion in part II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“When you want to hurry something, that means that you no longer care about it and want to get on to other things.” - Robert M. Pirsig in Zen and The Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just a Test Post From Blogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/just-a-test-post-from-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/just-a-test-post-from-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Yihui Xie gifted the RStats world with another presentation surface.  Now you can easily produce Hugo generated blogs right from RStudio!  Oh, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few bloggers blogging on blogs about this blog generator, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve got the basics of github down you might just go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34;&gt;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>