<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>management on Cattleguard Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in management on Cattleguard Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel Slightly Better About Your Capability Maturity Model Work</title>
      <link>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</guid>
      <description>During the course of your information security management and reporting you may find yourself in need of a tool for soliciting feedback to assess program operational capabilities. It may be useful to employ a Capability Maturity Model to gauge the emotional current state of a given practice.
Once you’ve gathered responses, you have to decide what to do with them. It’s not uncommon to average out the responses and use that as an indication of level state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Apply Google&#39;s CausalImpact Package to Analyze Infosec Intervention</title>
      <link>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</guid>
      <description>Google released their CausalImpact package a few years ago and when they did my mind started racing with ideas for information security and information risk applications.
Imagine if you could propose a control, policy change or process improvement with an expected effect on a response variable, which would lead you to purposefully defining a way to measure intervention outcomes. Not bad. You go on to determine a number of covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Keys for Successful Products and Programs Before You Even Start</title>
      <link>/2017/11/15/product-and-program-success-before-you-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/15/product-and-program-success-before-you-start/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been an information security practitioner for more than a few years, you’ve likely witnessed your share of disappointing purchases, implementations and initiatives.
If you’ve been charged with managing multiple information security projects, you might have experienced a torrent of failure.
So, why are some initiatives destined for glory while others board the bullet train to the Abyss of Embarrassment? Don’t like that one? The budget incinerator?
Let’s take a look at applying value chain concepts while examining some of the external pressures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>