<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infosec on Scenario 1</title>
    <link>/tags/infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infosec on Scenario 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel Slightly Better About Your Capability Maturity Model Work</title>
      <link>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</guid>
      <description>During the course of your information security management and reporting you may find yourself in need of a tool for soliciting feedback to assess program operational capabilities. It may be useful to employ a Capability Maturity Model to gauge the emotional current state of a given practice.
Once you’ve gathered responses, you have to decide what to do with them. It’s not uncommon to average out the responses and use that as an indication of level state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Apply Google&#39;s CausalImpact Package to Analyze Infosec Intervention</title>
      <link>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</guid>
      <description>Google released their CausalImpact package a few years ago and when they did my mind started racing with ideas for information security and information risk applications.
Imagine if you could propose a control, policy change or process improvement with an expected effect on a response variable, which would lead you to purposefully defining a way to measure intervention outcomes. Not bad. You go on to determine a number of covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Sankey!
Sankey diagrams for infosec</title>
      <link>/2017/05/19/sankey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/19/sankey/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, a tweet caught my eye.
It was something that I know I’d seen before, but it somehow had escaped my memory as to what it was called or how it was constructed. Well, it bugged me enough that I had to track it down.
It was the Sankey Chart.
tweet from @wendynather
 You can view the original tweet here.
As I am currently neck deep in writing an annual risk report it’d be easy for me to agree with the thought.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>