<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Cattleguard Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Cattleguard Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>My Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Simple Factor Analysis for Information Risk (FAIR) in R</title>
      <link>/2020/06/03/simplified-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/03/simplified-fair/</guid>
      <description>:::cropped version::: of a Photo by Annie Spratt on Unsplash
As I move on to other things for a while, I wanted to leave just one more example of how you might be able to test-drive FAIR using R in a stripped down form.
library(tidyverse)library(mc2d)estimates &amp;lt;- data.frame(onto=c(&amp;quot;TEF&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Vuln&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;Magnitude&amp;quot;), minZ=c(.1, .25, 100), modeZ = c(.2, .4, 1000), maxZ = c(.4, .75, 10000), shapeZ=c(4,4,2), stringsAsFactors = FALSE)# Just a test data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel Slightly Better About Your Capability Maturity Model Work</title>
      <link>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/16/likert-capability-maturity-models/</guid>
      <description>During the course of your information security management and reporting you may find yourself in need of a tool for soliciting feedback to assess program operational capabilities. It may be useful to employ a Capability Maturity Model to gauge the emotional current state of a given practice.
Once you’ve gathered responses, you have to decide what to do with them. It’s not uncommon to average out the responses and use that as an indication of level state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Apply Google&#39;s CausalImpact Package to Analyze Infosec Intervention</title>
      <link>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/12/counter-factual-infosec/</guid>
      <description>Google released their CausalImpact package a few years ago and when they did my mind started racing with ideas for information security and information risk applications.
Imagine if you could propose a control, policy change or process improvement with an expected effect on a response variable, which would lead you to purposefully defining a way to measure intervention outcomes. Not bad. You go on to determine a number of covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning Practice Pt1 - Steak Stats</title>
      <link>/2017/11/17/data-cleaning-practice-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/17/data-cleaning-practice-pt1/</guid>
      <description>Our family is in the habit of heading west. As such, we&amp;rsquo;ve passed through Amarillo, TX a time or two. I&amp;rsquo;ve even stopped into the Big Texan once for breakfast.
For miles down I-40 you&amp;rsquo;ll see billboards for this restaurant and brewery advertising a free 72oz steak, if you can eat it.
An office debate erupted amongst two of my colleagues over just what types of people end up beating the beast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>